hoosierlottery.com 2019-06-09

# Hoosier Lottery - privacy policy

## Effective April 15, 2018

**I. Introduction and definitions**

The Hoosier Lottery, its agents, contractors, and any other relevant parties, including IGT Indiana, LLC and IGT Global Solutions Corporation (together, referred to as the “Hoosier Lottery”) have established the following Privacy Policy to assist in the protection of data and information we obtain from users of [www.hoosierlottery.com](http://www.hoosierlottery.com/), including the myLOTTERY program. This Privacy Policy describes and applies to the collection, sharing, use, and storage of all information received, including but not limited to, information obtained from natural persons through [www.hoosierlottery.com](http://www.hoosierlottery.com/) and related web pages (“Website”), the app and social media.

We may modify this Privacy Policy at any time. We will notify you of material changes through whatever means are practical, as permitted by law, including labeling the Privacy Policy as “updated”.

If you find our privacy policies or any changes to this Policy unacceptable, you have the right to delete your myLOTTERY account, discontinue visiting [www.hoosierlottery.com](http://www.hoosierlottery.com/), uninstall our mobile app and otherwise stop or limit your electronic interactions with us.

By interacting electronically with the Hoosier Lottery through the Website, you consent to and accept this Privacy Policy. 

When we use the terms “we”, “us” or “our” in this Policy, we mean the Hoosier Lottery. The terms “user”, “you” or “your” refer to you as a person who interacts with the Hoosier Lottery and may provide data or information to us.

When we use the term “Personal Information" in this Policy, we mean information about a natural person that identifies that person, including the following:

  * first and last name;
  * home or other physical address, including street name and name of a city or town;
  * e-mail address;
  * telephone number;
  * other identifier that permits the physical or online contact of a natural person; and
  * information concerning a natural person that is collected online and maintained in personally identifiable form in combination with another identifier such as name or address.

A domain name, location, or Internet protocol address is not considered Personal Information.

**II. What types of information do we collect from you?**

We collect and use various types of information to optimize your Hoosier Lottery interactive experience, to understand our interactive users and lottery players, and to gather data for analysis so we can improve our interactive features and product offering.

We do not collect Personal Information that is not relevant to us in conducting our business.

**A. Information you choose to share:** we collect and use information that you choose to share with us when you communicate with us or sign up for an interaction with us.

  * Emails, Surveys & Electronic Newsletter Subscriptions: If you participate in a survey, send an email to us, or subscribe to an electronic newsletter, the Website will gather the following information, some of which may be considered Personal Information:
    * the email address you use and contents of the email you send;
    * information volunteered in response to a survey; and
    * other information required by or volunteered on the electronic newsletter subscription form.
  * Social Media and RSS Feeds: If you “like,” follow the Hoosier Lottery, or otherwise contact the Hoosier Lottery via social media (e.g., Facebook or Twitter), or subscribe to the Hoosier Lottery via RSS feed by using the Website, the Website will collect the following information:
    * the social media username you used (e.g., Facebook or Twitter username);
    * the number of “likes;” and
    * the total number of subscribers to our RSS feeds (but will not track where you posted the feeds).
  * myLOTTERY: Registering for and using the myLOTTERY program will result in us collecting information, including but not limited to the following: 
    * Registration of Personal Information   
We collect the following Personal Information at initial registration. Some registration information may be optional; some information will be necessary for the creation and administration of a myLOTTERY account:
      * birthdate;
      * gender;
      * name (first, last);
      * address;
      * ZIP code;
      * email address;
      * password (self-selected); and
      * telephone numbers.
    * Voluntarily disclosed information  
Once you have registered for a myLOTTERY account, we will provide you with opportunities to volunteer additional information (not Personal Information) including the following:
      * lottery-related preferences (e.g., favorite games);
      * communication-related preferences (e.g., frequency of e-mails containing winning numbers); and
      * answers to occasional survey questions.

    * Information obtained from myLOTTERY functions integrated into the Hoosier Lottery Mobile Convenience Application (“App”)  
The Hoosier Lottery may integrate myLOTTERY into its App. If it does, we will collect Personal Information on myLOTTERY users from the App in addition to the Website. The information we collect on the App and how we use it will be similar to the Website and will comply with this Policy.

**Other information we receive:** By visiting [www.hoosierlottery.com](http://www.hoosierlottery.com/) (including browsing, viewing rules or winning numbers), we will automatically collect and store information about your visit, including the following:

  * Technical information about the Internet protocol (“IP”) address, browser and operating system that you use. Location may also be identified via geo-filtering of the IP address.
  * The date and time of your visit.
  * The web pages or services you access on the Website.
  * The website you visited prior to coming to [www.hoosierlottery.com](http://www.hoosierlottery.com/).
  * The website you visited as you left [www.hoosierlottery.com](http://www.hoosierlottery.com/).
  * Ad(s) that you clicked on to access [www.hoosierlottery.com](http://www.hoosierlottery.com/).
  * If the ShareThis feature is used, the content shared from [www.hoosierlottery.com](http://www.hoosierlottery.com/), with whom content is shared, and where content is posted.
  * If you download forms or other documents, the forms or documents that you downloaded.
  * The name of the country in which your server is located.

We collect this information by using standard methods of automatic information collection used by other website providers, including:

  * _**Cookies:  **_Cookies are small pieces of data stored locally in the temporary memory of your web browser. We use cookies and similar technologies to provide our services and understand our users. 
    * Cookies distinguish you from other visitors to [www.hoosierlottery.com](http://www.hoosierlottery.com/). [We](http://www.hoosierlottery.com/) use cookies in this way to enhance or customize a Person’s visit to the Website and to recognize that Person when he or she visits again. This makes the Website easier and faster for you to use while providing us with useful information about your use of the Website.
    * If you have concerns about the use of cookies, you can always act to prevent their activation and use, for example by changing the privacy settings in the browser that you use to access the Website. Because computer software and hardware is unique, your ability to manage cookies may require detailed steps that are not practical to explain here. Refusing or deleting cookies will limit the information that we can collect and store, and may also limit the ability to take advantage of some features of the Website.
  * _**Online advertising (including, but not limited to, video, social, and native advertising):**_  Online advertising will be used to advertise Hoosier Lottery products. We will track the number of clicks on ads for analytical and marketing purposes. 

**III. How do we use your information?**

We use the information we receive about you, including Personal Information, to conduct and enhance our business activities. More specifically, we may use data and information that we receive about you to:

  * Administer [www.hoosierlottery.com](http://www.hoosierlottery.com/) and the myLOTTERY program and other player accounts.
  * Send you requested information or respond to your questions.
  * Confirm you are eligible to play our games or participate in our promotions.
  * Contact you for research and survey opportunities.
  * Fulfill the specific purpose for which it was volunteered.
  * Track use of [www.hoosierlottery.com](http://www.hoosierlottery.com/) for internal research.
  * Improve use of our interactive services.
  * Customize content for you.
  * Notify you about promotions, special offers, etc.
  * Provide relevant information to certain service providers in connection with our legitimate business purposes.
  * Generate aggregate statistical studies and use the results for marketing and responsible gaming initiatives.
  * With the assistance of third-party companies, use only non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your use of the Website or myLOTTERY in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you.
  * Protect and enforce our rights and property or the rights and property of others.
  * Enforce this Policy.
  * Fulfill certain obligations under law or regulation.
  * Execute other legitimate business purposes.

While you are allowing us to collect, store, and use the information we receive about you, you always own your information. Integrity is important to us, which is why we do not use collected information for commercial marketing. We do not sell or rent your Personal Information to anyone.

We may provide certain information to contractors for research or other purposes, including but not limited to disclosing Website traffic information to improve the use of the Website to our users, ensuring compliance with contractual requirements for data use, and to help us with business activities such as fulfilling promotional prizes. These third parties are contractually required to use this information only for what is necessary to perform required functions.

We may ask for your consent to use your information in certain ways outside of our ordinary practices. If we do that, you will be given the opportunity to choose whether or not we use your information in this manner.

If you voluntarily provide information to us, you will be deemed to have consented to the collection and use of this information for the above-described purposes, subject to state and federal laws.

**IV. When do we disclose your information?**

We will not disclose Personal Information to others unless:

  * you provide appropriate consent in advance of our disclosure; or
  * we are permitted or required by law to disclose.

As part of winning prizes from the Hoosier Lottery, it is our policy to reserve the right to share and display some of your information on our website and social media pages.  Claimants may have their first and last name, photo, hometown, and prize amount shared or displayed in these locations.  We may be required by law to disclose your information. If a valid legal process, such as a subpoena, court order, or search warrant, requires us to disclose certain information, we will do so. We will comply with laws and regulations regarding notice and opportunity for you to object to these required disclosures. If there is an opportunity for you to object to certain disclosures, it is up to you to object or take other action to prevent those disclosures.

In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Policy and any state or federal laws, including the Indiana Access to Public Records Act, the state or federal laws will control.

**V. How do we protect your information?**

We take actions as necessary to prevent unauthorized access to your information by a person other than you or us. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural security measures for all information systems under our control so that information will not be lost, misused, or altered. For site security purposes and to ensure that our Internet services remain available to all users, the Hoosier Lottery uses software programs to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage. In the event of authorized law enforcement investigations and pursuant to any required legal process, information from these sources may be used to help identify an individual.

If your Personal Information is protected by state or federal law, including the Indiana Access to Public Records Act, we will comply with that law and the rulings of a court or other judicial or quasi-judicial body in interpreting that law.

We cannot guarantee that these measures will prevent every unauthorized attempt to access, use, or disclose your information, including Personal Information.

**VI. What access do you have to your information and what choices can you make about your information?**

In addition to measures already mentioned in this Privacy Policy, such as managing cookies, you have some choices in accessing and managing your information.

If you register for advanced services such as mylottery functionality, you may disable your account or edit account information and communication preferences upon request, by emailing, phoning or faxing the Hoosier Lottery. Upon deactivation, please understand that, despite deactivation of an account online, state record retention laws may require the Hoosier Lottery to maintain information about your account.

If you believe that your Personal Information is not being handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy, you can contact IGT Indiana’s Director of Corporate Social Responsibility and Compliance, who will discuss the issue with you, conduct an investigation, and report back to you in an attempt to resolve the issues quickly and amicably.

**VII. Additional policy considerations**

This Privacy Policy is designed to protect Personal Information and privacy rights as they are currently understood, and to satisfy applicable rules and regulations. The text of this Privacy Policy cannot address every potential issue and circumstance. It is the policy of the Hoosier Lottery to adhere to data protection regulations of the State of Indiana and applicable federal regulations. This Privacy Policy may be changed from time to time in accordance with applicable laws and evolving business needs. This Policy will be available on the Website and other relevant public interfaces.

California law entitles California residents to request additional information about what personally identifiable information a company shares with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing efforts. The Hoosier Lottery does not share your information with third parties for the third parties’ own direct marketing purposes. If you have questions about our practices or your rights under California law, please write to us at Hoosier Lottery Privacy Policy c/o General Counsel, 1302 N. Meridian St., Indianapolis, IN 46202.

## Hoosier Lottery Mobile Application

**I. Introduction and definitions**

The Hoosier Lottery, its agents, contractors, and other relevant parties, including IGT Indiana, LLC and IGT Global Solutions Corporation (together, referred to as the “Hoosier Lottery”) have established the following Privacy Policy to assist in the protection of data and information we obtain from users of the Hoosier Lottery Mobile Application (“App”). This Privacy Policy describes and applies to the collection, sharing, use, and storage of all information received, including but not limited to, information obtained from natural persons through the App, including through the myLOTTERY program.

We may modify this Privacy Policy at any time. We will notify you of material changes through whatever means are practical, as permitted by law, including labeling the Privacy Policy as “updated”.

If you find this Privacy Policy unacceptable, you have the right to discontinue using the App, delete your myLOTTERY account, or delete the App from your mobile device. By interacting electronically with the Hoosier Lottery through the App, you consent to and accept this Privacy Policy. 

When we use the terms “we”, “us” or “our” in this Policy, we mean the Hoosier Lottery. The terms “user”, “you”, or “your” refer to you as a person who interacts with the Hoosier Lottery and may provide data or information to us.

When we use the term “Personal Information" in this Policy, we mean information about a natural person that identifies that person. Personal Information includes a natural person’s:

  * first and last name;
  * home or other physical address, including street name and name of a city or town;
  * e-mail address;
  * telephone number;
  * social security number;
  * other identifier that permits the physical or online contact of a natural person; and
  * information concerning a natural person that is collected online and maintained in personally identifiable form in combination with another identifier such as name, address, and social security number.

A domain name, location, or Internet protocol address is not considered Personal Information.

**II. What types of information do we collect from you?**

We collect and use various types of information when you download and use the App, to optimize your Hoosier Lottery interactive experience, to understand our interactive users and lottery players, and to gather data for analysis so we can improve the App. 

When you download and use the App, it will automatically collect and store information about your visit, including the following:

  * Technical information about the Internet protocol (“IP”) address, mobile phone number, internet service, type of device, and operating system that you use.
  * Your location, via GPS, phone location services, or geo-filtering of the IP address.
  * The date and time of your visit.
  * The pages or services you access on the App.
  * The name of the country in which your server is located.
  * If you use the Facebook sharing feature, information regarding your share, including your Facebook username, with whom content is shared, and where content is posted.
  * If you downloaded forms or other documents, the forms or documents that you downloaded.
  * If you use the App to scan a game ticket, information about that ticket and the game it is associated with, and if you later entered that ticket into a 2nd Chance contest.

We collect this information by using standard methods of automatic information collection used by other App providers, including Cookies and data from advertising. 

If you use the App to register for and use the myLOTTERY program, we will collect information specific to that registration and use, including the following:

  * Registration of Personal Information   
We collect the following Personal Information at initial registration. Some registration information may be optional; some information will be necessary for the creation and administration of a myLOTTERY account:
  * Voluntarily disclosed information

    * Birthdate.
    * Gender.
    * Name (first, last).
    * Address.
    * ZIP code.
    * Email address.
    * Password (self-selected).
    * Telephone numbers.

Once you have registered for a myLOTTERY account, we will provide you with opportunities to volunteer additional information (not Personal Information) including the following:

    * Lottery-related preferences (e.g., favorite games).
    * Communication-related preferences (e.g., frequency of e-mails containing winning numbers).
    * Answers to occasional survey questions.
    * If you use your myLOTTERY account to enter 2nd Chance promotions, the entry code or serial number you use to enter a 2nd Chance promotion.

**  III. How do we use your information?**

We use the information we receive about you, including Personal Information, to conduct and enhance our business activities. More specifically, we may use data and information that we receive about you to:

  * Administer the App and the myLOTTERY program.
  * Track use of the App and myLOTTERY for internal research.
  * Improve use of our interactive services.
  * Customize content for you.
  * Notify you about promotions and special offers.
  * Provide relevant information to certain service providers in connection with our legitimate business purposes.
  * Generate aggregate statistical studies and use the results for marketing and responsible gaming initiatives.
  * Confirm that you are eligible to play our games or participate in our promotions.
  * With the assistance of third-party companies, use only non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, time and date, information about games you scanned) during your use of myLOTTERY in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you.
  * Protect and enforce our rights and property or the rights and property of others.
  * Enforce this Policy.
  * Fulfill certain obligations under law or regulation.
  * Execute other legitimate business purposes.

While you are allowing us to collect, store, and use the information we receive about you, you always own your information. Integrity is important to us, which is why we do not use collected information for commercial marketing. We do not sell or rent your Personal Information to anyone.

 We may provide certain information to contractors for research or other purposes, including but not limited to disclosing Website traffic information to improve the use of the Website to our users. These third parties are contractually required to use this information only for what is necessary to perform required functions.

We may ask for your consent to use your information in certain ways outside of our ordinary practices. If we do that, you will be given the opportunity to choose whether or not we use your information in this manner.

**IV. When do we disclose your information?**

We will not disclose Personal Information to others unless:

  * you provide appropriate consent in advance of our disclosure; or
  * we are permitted or required by law to disclose.

We may be required by law to disclose your information. If a valid legal process, such as a subpoena, court order, or search warrant, requires us to disclose certain information, we will do so. We will comply with laws and regulations regarding notice and opportunity for you to object to these required disclosures. If there is an opportunity for you to object to certain disclosures, it is up to you to object or take other action to prevent those disclosures.

In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Policy and any state or federal laws, including the Indiana Access to Public Records Act, the state or federal laws will control.

**V. How do we protect your information?**

We take actions as necessary to prevent unauthorized access to your information by a person other than you or us. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural security measures for all information systems under our control so that information will not be lost, misused, or altered. For site security purposes and to ensure that our Internet services remain available to all users, the Hoosier Lottery uses software programs to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage. In the event of authorized law enforcement investigations and pursuant to any required legal process, information from these sources may be used to help identify an individual.

If your Personal Information is protected by state or federal law, including the Indiana Access to Public Records Act, we will comply with that law and the rulings of a court or other judicial or quasi-judicial body in interpreting that law.

We cannot guarantee that these measures will prevent every unauthorized attempt to access, use, or disclose your information, including Personal Information.

VI. What access do you have to your information and what choices can you make about your information?

You may discontinue using the App, uninstall the App, disable your myLOTTERY account, or edit your account information and communications preferences to eliminate our ability to gather additional data and information from your use of the App. Upon uninstallation or disablement of the App or your account, please understand that record retention laws may require us to maintain information about you and your account.

If you believe that your Personal Information is not being handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy, you can contact IGT Indiana’s Director of Corporate Social Responsibility and Compliance, who will discuss the issue with you, conduct an investigation, and report back to you in an attempt to resolve the issues quickly and amicably.

**VII. Effective date**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of April 15, 2018.

**VIII. Additional policy considerations**

This Privacy Policy is designed to protect Personal Information and privacy rights as they are currently understood, and to satisfy applicable rules and regulations. The text of this Privacy Policy cannot address every potential issue and circumstance. It is the policy of the Hoosier Lottery to adhere to data protection regulations of the State of Indiana and applicable federal regulations. This Privacy Policy may be changed from time to time in accordance with applicable laws and evolving business needs. This Policy will be available on the App and other relevant public interfaces.

California law entitles California residents to request additional information about what personally identifiable information a company shares with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing efforts. The Hoosier Lottery does not share your information with third parties for the third parties’ own direct marketing purposes. If you have questions about our practices or your rights under California law, please write to us at Hoosier Lottery Privacy Policy c/o General Counsel, 1302 N. Meridian St., Indianapolis, IN 46202.

Must be 18 or older to play. Please Play Responsibly.
